

Software Engineer

joashagesa@yahoo.com V

in





## About

My name is Joash Agesa, a bachelor of computer software Engineering student and a freelance software engineer. My passion for software lies with dreaming up ideas and making them come true with elegant interfaces. I take great care in the experience, architecture, and code quality of the things I build.

I am also an open-source enthusiast. I love how collaboration and knowledge sharing happens through opensource and I am happy to see what I do could eventually feedback to the community and industry.

## **Projects**

#### CodeGround O 7

An Educational Online Code Editor powered by Al Documentation



#### 100 days Challenge ♥ 7

100 days of design challenge



#### Beeetle 7

An embeddable Chat Wigdet with ai powered conversation

More Projects...

### Work Experience

#### **VIRTUALWEB TECHNOLOGIES** Software Engineer

Jun 2023 - Present | Remote

In Automation and Solutions Department

- Developed mobile applications driving business operations
- Created Script Automations for the business cloud monitoring
- Designed and Developed the Cloud Access Portal for end users

SiafuSocial Ltd. Technical Lead

May 2023 - Nov 2023 | Nairobi, Kenya

In Product R & D and Engineering Architecture Department

- Collaboratively remediated 120+ software anomalies, contributing to user-centric features via reusable code.
- Verified and optimized feasibility of 100+ UI/UX designs for 2+ applications.
- Implementing security measures such as encryption, authentication, and authorization.
- Optimizing backend code and database queries to improve application performance and response times.

# Stacks

Frontend TypeScript, JavaScript, Vue, Nuxt, React, Next.js, Vite

Backend Node, MongoDB, MySQL, Serverless, Nginx, Docker, Dokku

Mobile Android, Kotlin, React Native, PWA

DevOps Firebase, AWS, Azure

Languages Python, Java, C/C++, C#, Go

## Education

Computer Software Engineering, Bachelor of Science - BS, Kirinyaga University

Sep 2019 - Sep 2023

# Languages

Swahili (Native speaker), English (Fluent), Japanese (Beginner)

Online Version

Last updated at February 17th 2024, 1:53:03 am